There are other worlds than these.
The Dark Tower is a fantasy, action, science
fiction film directed by Nikolaj Arcel.
A boy haunted by visions of a parallel world aids its disillusioned guardian in
preventing the destruction of the nexus of universes known as the Dark Tower.
Roland Deschain, played by Idris Elba.
Walter O’Dim, played by Matthew McConaughey.
Jake Chambers, played by Tom Taylor.
Arra Champignon, played by Claudia Kim.
Pimli Prentiss, played by Fran Kranz.
Tirana, played by Abbey Lee.
The Dark Tower is a 2017 American neo-Western science fantasy film
loosely based on Stephen King's novel series of the same name.
Directed and co-written by Nikolaj Arcel, the film stars Idris Elba as Roland Deschain, a gunslinger on a quest to protect the Dark Tower—a mythical structure which
supports all realities—while Matthew McConaughey plays his nemesis Walter Padick, and Tom Taylor stars as Jake Chambers, a boy who becomes Roland's apprentice.
Intended as the first installment in a multimedia franchise, the film combines various elements from the eight-novel series, mostly from the first
and third volumes, and takes place in both modern-day New York City and in Mid-World, Roland's Old West-style parallel universe.
The film also serves as a sequel to the novels.
The production of the film was complex and difficult, as
production began ten years before the release of the film.
Efforts to adapt The Dark Tower series for the screen started in
2007, with periodic reports and official announcements.
The project was then shelved before the rights were
transitioned to a different production company.
Development experienced starts and stops with various filmmakers and studios at
different times, including Universal Pictures, Paramount Pictures, Warner Bros.
Pictures, and Lionsgate Entertainment.
The adaptation went through three major phases of planning: with J.
Abrams from 2007 to 2009, Ron Howard from 2010 to 2015, and finally, the current iteration, announced in March 2015, produced by
Sony Pictures Entertainment and Media Rights Capital, with Arcel directing and Howard remaining in a producing role.
The Dark Tower premiered at the Museum of Modern Art in New York City on July 31, 2017, and was
theatrically released in the United States by Sony Pictures Releasing on August 4, 2017.
The film grossed $113.2 million worldwide on a $66 million budget and received generally negative reviews, with criticism aimed at its compression of the
multiple-novel source material into a single film, though Elba's performance, Holkenborg’s musical score, and the action sequences earned praise.
The film explores themes of mind control, gunslinger, based
on novel or book, portal, parallel world.
The tone is dark and thought_provoking.